

RAMÓN IVÁN PUÓN MERAZ

CONTACT DETAILS

- Linkedin Profile
- Github Profile
- Cell Phone: (+52)9616103856
- · ramon.puon@gmail.com
- · Location: Mexico

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib,
- Spanish Native
- Seaborn)
- English C1 -Advanced
- HTML, CSS,
 Javascript
- React Library
- Webpack
- R (Bioconductor)

RELEVANT COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Introduction to Data Science in Python, Coursera
- Python for Genomic Data Science, Coursera
- Data Manipulation and Analysis with Pandas and Python , Platzi
- Frontend Developer Practical Course, Platzi
- React.js Practical Course, Platzi
- Javascript Practical Course, Platzi
- Webpack course, Platzi

PROFILE

Self-taught and highly motivated **data scientist**, focused in writing clear and concise code. Interested in implementing my knowledge in statistics, and research experience, to turn data into useful, business insights.

For more info, and details of my **projects**, visit my personal Web Portfolio

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Radiohead Data Analysis

Using the python library spotipy, you can extract data from the Spotipy API. An analysis of the audio features of the Radiohead catalogue was performed using pandas and seaborn for data visualization. Work in progress

Sea Level Predictor.

Freecodecamp project. Analysis of a dataset documenting average sea level rise of the world's oceans. Using the linear regression function in Scipy, a prediction of sea level rise in 2050 was carried out.

Cumbres Blancas Website

Contributions to the implementation of web design for the site of the Mexican organization Cumbres Blancas, an environmental NGO.

RELATED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Development Personal Projects.

September 2021 — Current (4 months)

I am currently developing projects, with the aim of adapting to using the latest frontend tools and obtaining experience in data visualization and analysis.

Data Visualization of Environmental Microbiology Project

August 2019 — June 2021 (2 years)

Implementation of python library matplotlib to present results in master's thesis project. Statistical analysis of these results was carried out in Minitab.

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN BIOTECHNOLOGY INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO Y DE ESTUDIOS SUPERIORES DE MONTERREY (ITESM), PUEBLA

August 2019 - June 2021

Thesis Project: "Characterization of the chromium reduction activity of an endemic bacterium from the Atoyac river with potential use in water bioremediation"

BIOTECHNOLOGY ENGINEERING
INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO Y DE ESTUDIOS SUPERIORES DE
MONTERREY (ITESM), PUEBLA

January 2015 - June 2019